Guide to the William A. Moore Collection - Papers, Local 696, 1970-1997 IBT0063
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
William A. Moore Collection - Papers, Local 696
1970-1997
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0063
3 Linear Feet 2 record center cartons
The collection consists of files assembled by William Moore during the course of his long association with Teamsters Local 696, Topeka, Kansas. They pertain largely to Teamsters national and international elections, Teamsters conventions, labor law, and legal matters.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Moore, 2015 [2015.041].
Arrangement
Files are arranged by subject.
Biographical / Historical
William Moore is a third generation Teamster from IBT Local 696, Topeka, Kansas. He became a Teamster member in the early 1970s working in meat packing, freight and warehouse jobs in the Topeka area. In 1973 he became Business Agent for Local 696 and served as Trustee, Recording Secretary, and Secretary-Treasurer, before becoming President of the local in 1993. In 1991 Moore became IBT Central Region chairman for UPS and served on the national UPS negotiating team. He also served as Organizing Director of the Central Region. In 2013 he began to work full-time as an International Representative for the IBT.
Scope and Contents
The William Moore files mainly pertain to Teamsters national and international elctions and the 1996 International Convention. Other files pertain to labor law and legal matters. Printed materials such as issues of the Teamster magazine are also included in the collection. Series 2 contains truck models pertaining to companies and other entities connected to the Teamsters.
Bib#
17257796
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions
- US Labor Management Relations Act of 1947, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- US Department of Labor Labor-Management Service Administration Pamphlets, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Teamster Election Regulations, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Teamster Convention Information, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Supreme Court of the United States Ruling and Opinions, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Picketing, No Date (Box 3, Folder 6)
- National Labor Relations Board History and Rulings, 1970-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Labor Law Reports, 1977-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Kansas Worker's and Medical Compensation Act Statutes, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Kansas State Court Decisions, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- General Labor Law Materials, 1976-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- James P. Hoffa and Ron Carey Local 696, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- James P. Hoffa General Local 696, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- James P. Hoffa General Loal 696, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- James P. Hoffa General Local 696, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- James P. Hoffa Convention Materials Local 696, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Assorted Labor Publications Local 696, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- The Teamster Leader Local 696, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Teamster Media Coverage Local 696, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Teamster Magazine (1 of 3), 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- The Teamster Magazine (2 of 3), 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- The Teamster Magazine (3 of 3), 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Dan F. Darrow Campaign, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General Election Materials, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Walter Shea Campaign, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- R.V. Durham Campaign, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ron Carey and R.V. Durham Campaigns, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ron Carey Campaign, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ron Carey Action Faxes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ron Carey, Conferences and Finances, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Ron Carey, Corruption and Reform, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Ron Carey General, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ron Carey General, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ron Carey General, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ron Carey and the Media, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- William J. McCarthy Controversy, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- IBT Convention Election Results, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- IBT Convention Online, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- National Elections, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Dues/Per Capita Tax Referendum, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Truck Models
  Arrangement
  Truck Models are boxed in original packaging if available. Items are described at the box level.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains truck models collected by William Moore from companies connected to the Teamsters.
  - Miscellaneous Truck Models: Roadway, Penjoy, UPS, Undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Truck Models: Penjoy, UPS, Yellow, JC 3, Ertl, Undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Truck Models: UPS, Time DC, IBT Local 41, Undated (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Truck Models: UPS, Nash Finch, IBT Local 63, IBT Local 120, Ohio Conference of Teamsters, JC 25, Undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Truck Models: Penjoy, ABP, Oklahoma City Police, Undated (Box 8)
- The Heroes vs. the soreheads: a short history of the teamster reform movement, 1994-1999; IBT 0063 (Box Shared Box 30, Folder 4)